hello welcome to friday today's question
is
what is in it for me so with our
individual projects or
game b if gamefee's your project what is
how would you sell it to someone else
how would you answer to somebody what's
in it for me
and i don't want to start with my
projects my brain's still waking up i'm
trying to have my second coffee
so if someone else wants to start that'd
be great
i can start um and
bentley i can't actually hear you i'm
not sure if i've heard you yet so i'm
not sure if you're having like issues
again
yeah i'll keep going all right so uh
what's in it for
for me um for wiki election and just the
conversation around fighting
misinformation in general i mean i've
had this conversation
i think a thousand times over the last
uh couple of months
where i think just globally we're in a
trust vacuum right now and that affects
everything
that affects the ability you know for uh
like for people to actually know
what's going on and for important things
whether it's you know the coronavirus
whether it's vaccines in general whether
it's climate change
for all of that thing for all of those
things um
it's hard for people to know what to
trust if they don't trust the government
or the media and they don't know which
experts being
you know shown are actually worthy of
of trust especially if they conflict
with each other um
which obviously i think that makes it
clear what's in it for the average
person
but like for what's in it from a game a
space i think a part of it
is both like corporations and
governments
are now fighting a very uphill battle
when it comes to like if you actually
have something
worthy of sharing and you have something
that you think is true
how do you differentiate that from all
the other noise out there
and so i mean it's being able to get
your point across in a way that
is hopefully worthy of trust um
unfortunately for them it means that if
it's not worthy of trust
that's not the point it's not to let
anybody talk it's to let what's
trustworthy get to to the top so i guess
that that's kind of it
is if your story is worth telling then
ideally it should surface and it should
be given more weight amongst all the
other noise
i don't know what's going on here i mean
all right does that matter yeah all
right
um yes so uh
for reason score there's several
different since it's kind of a tool that
fits in other things or several
different use cases so
for like the goalie bot version it's
just kind of a resource
like um like
a politifact or snopes
except that it gets into deeper broader
subjects
and then with this you can also be a
part of
that fact-finding process so you can add
facts to it
well you could suggest them in the
goalie bot
process and since all the suggestions
are on twitter it's
anyone can see if i've ignored your
suggestion or goalie bot has
so it'd just be kind of a central
resource for facts and stuff
and then the reason score tool uh i hope
it will be useful
later on for people like if you're
trying to make a decision in an open
cooperative or a group
kind of like this if there's a
contentious issue
maybe it would help with that where you
want to use evidence to make the
decision
usually on large decisions and
yeah and then for the goalie bot side
just go back to that if you're trying to
vote
on some
initiative in your town city or federal
government
it would be a resource to go to to get
uh a lay of all the facts and the
evidence
so that yeah i think that would cover
most of it
i can go next my coffee's kicked in a
little bit
although now there's a kid screaming the
next room so that's fun
there's what is my project um
that was a reason score that's not the
name solution raising
what's in it for people is i will get
rid of all of your screaming children
that is that is the next solution
raising um
i don't know whether to answer it for
right now or the future of solutionizing
and so i will answer it for right now to
come to solution raising what's in it
for you
because if you don't know what's in it
for you you're probably not my people
yet so that is fine but for the right
person what's in it for them is to be
able to
come have a conversation and generate
actual solutions
that are feasibly possible and so to be
part of
a hopeful conversation that these things
are
doable with out needing mass buy-in at
the billions level
can be at the thousands level and we can
have massive impact
right away and then it's working finding
the people to
to get to be a part of figuring out
how we actually create a process for 10
000 people
and figure out the infrastructure and
technology
we need to be able to do that whole
process
so that's what's in it for them
matush do you want to go you you go
facebook
okay uh so my project's name is
hyperlogos and it's a
data mapping and visualization tool uh
which is something i wanted to do for
many many years and i finally got to the
stage when
um i can start showing it more publicly
and
uh possibly get uh some help
something like that so uh what's new for
me is basically
getting this thing
done or at least in progress so um
something like now getting my dream real
which is
very important to me and um i see it as
like doing my own thing
which i will be doing anyway uh but in
this context in context of of
me gaming the possibilities are
much broader than in like normal
um normal context so to speak
and i hope for it to be useful not only
to myself as originally intended but
also for
other people and yeah for general public
hopefully so that's my
thing
okay so about the third place what's in
it for me
um i think it's it's more to do with
sort of like human connection and that
you don't need pounds
or algorithms to actually find find each
other and to actually create a space
that people can drop into without any
barriers and help them to develop
things that they they want to go up they
want to go off and do
and help them and provide art stuff so i
think what's in it for me is just that a
sensible longing and um
not being left made to feel less than i
suppose
you know i mean so um and being part of
a bigger network
which is connected with others as well
so um i think that's the biggest
main thing because the money doesn't
motivate me at all
i wish it did because then i'd probably
like yeah you could do this that the
other if i was one of them but um
probably wouldn't appeal to gay male
players because he wouldn't understand
it
because to them humans don't really have
much value at all
you know but um tech apps and everything
and whatever yeah
they do but i'm more interested in the
conversations
and the human connection and that's
what's in it for me
thanks everyone i feel like the question
was also a little um weirdly
stated but like what's in it for me like
what's in it for me
jubilee for solution raising well i know
it's in it for me that's why i'm there
but like what's in it for me
the random new person right like the the
customer
that either a gaming or game b like why
would they get involved right now right
and what would their biggest
piece be anyway but that was then i
write out the question how it is
heard is how is how it is answered which
is how it's kind of supposed to be
so you can open up the conversation from
here
that's the idea cafe that's what it's
designed to do each answer
then we can have an open conversation
which doesn't work
and and this is kind of out of the
spirit of
idea cafe but uh just diving right in so
marcus have you heard of open global
mind
yet yes i heard about it not that i
it's just a group of people that are
trying to create sense making tools as a
community or use
since making tools and create them um
put a link in the chat um but they would
be they might be interested in seeing
what you've built and maybe contributing
to some of the design if you're open to
that
or just using your tool this designer is
something like
someone i really really need because i
can do
uh designers i can do some of it but
yeah yeah and they're really loosely
yeah you know it's a loose group of
people so it might be a little
sometimes it's frustrating to come into
a community that all when it's well it's
like game b
right everyone wants to do something but
they all have different ideas on how it
is but
i'm finding it interesting uh they have
at least one weekly meeting
but check out the website watch the
videos it's jerry markowski
who has jerry's brain he's been using a
mind mapping tool which you've probably
seen the brain
for 20 years now so
yes it's pretty big yeah i had the
pleasure of meeting him
so yeah he's awesome so yeah so he's
doing
he's heading up open global mind so if
you have trouble like finding the way
into those meetings just let me know and
i'll figure it out
for the record i also wouldn't mind
having a meeting with matus just to see
your
your project because data visualization
is also something i'm
i'm extremely interested in so yeah
when's the
unveiling party the release party
well it almost happened like a few
months ago
when i was almost ready and uh it's
always this one week
before uh i am actually ready so
we've um
oh no i still cannot screen share here
so uh
not today but
if you want one of the things that might
help is if like me and you maybe even
bentley
like do a zoom meeting outside of this
time and record it
we don't necessarily have to publish
that video as is but there might end up
being like a really good you know five
or ten minute clip that you can snip out
and that might be a good intro like if
you want to you know sort of
have a teaser it won't be necessarily
nice to look at and it might be
a little bit meandering just because of
how those conversations go
but i personally like using that sort of
thing as like
the very first type of content uh
available
awesome that's a very good idea and yeah
let's do it
what sort of designer are you looking
for
um well uh
someone who can tell me where the pixels
are not right
and stuff like um
design in terms of user experience
because uh
you know everything that a developer
does
is kind of biased uh especially if it's
done
like in alone mode uh
totally biased and then someone who has
experience in
user interaction uh can take a look and
say
okay this is rubbish because a
standard user is not going to be able to
find stuff or
know how to do like lots of things and
it will be
um i think you you've seen it so
i guess for you it was kind of a weird
experience to
you know yes i broke it um
um because the reason why i ask is i've
seen someone
who was ui ux who's just joined the
project group so i'll need to go back
and look who that is
um maybe they could help out because he
just needs to know so like what you're
looking for
i was making like um last minute
uh changes and updates uh to make it uh
more useful uh and uh
yeah i guess when we have this quick
zoom meeting
and um i'll present what i have
currently
then we'll be able to talk more about
the next steps and announcing it
more publicly and then
the person
yeah okay i'm forgetting her name
because i've just seen like i'm
following her project
the was it the two row flow commons
if somebody knows her name please um
but she's actually like a a ui designer
that's her thing and
that's like the the the project that
she's in game before
is the two row uh flow
something commons forget the full name
um
but yeah that's her her specialty so
that might be
also worth which that might be a good
thing like if
i i from what i'm hearing it sounds like
one of the challenges that you're having
right now is being able to explain it
in a way that would get people
interested and that might be a good
outcome from the meeting with
with me and bentley is to sort of put
that into
terms that maybe we can find some
snippet somewhere in there
that then you can start to shop that
that clip around to say hey does this
thing sound interesting
that would be totally awesome because it
has so many angles
and you know it's really a project that
uh
started literally 25 years ago
uh as something different
but also connected to the general
theme of visualization and
yeah it's difficult to say what exactly
it is and what it should be doing
because it's um yeah it's way too
general
so uh on the meeting i'll explain more
and when you see it you will understand
perfect i think that will probably be a
good
a good combo because bentley is actually
a developer and sort of
ui ux focused and i'm not a developer
and ui
ux focus so that those sort of two sides
of that coin
i imagine will probably be a good a good
mix for some
initial feedback and then if you can
chop that around two
still can't remember her name but like
some of the people in the group who are
like
really you know ui ux will focus and
trained
then that will hopefully get you to
where you need to be
so one thing to answer the the question
that started this meeting is
what's in it for me and what would be in
it for
some uh people who have projects or
started doing something
is getting it to uh
to the public and uh what i mean is
uh slowly
uh do the unveiling of of the thing
and uh you know because
how i feel about um making it more
public is
there is some kind of uh like fear of uh
embarrassment about uh you know this
thing
maybe not being uh not having enough
relevance and not being good enough and
you know
when you work on something for uh long
enough it makes you
feel at least uneasy to uh to make it
public because
yeah the dream can be just
so uh for everyone who is who is
watching
uh uh i guess the
game b setting can be perfect for uh for
just this
uh helping with uh first assessment of
the project
and then um
helping with uh taking it further
from the standalone developer having a
dream mode
to uh something that actually works and
this is used by
other people so yeah
i think bentley wanted to say something
in the midst of that
yeah i was just gonna mention that i was
telling my wife i think i'm gonna
do a training in user experience
nice and uh shifts my career a little
bit that way keep doing the software
development but
it's a little bit more fun totally
[Laughter]
not so much time fiddling with things
is user experience something you need to
have a lot of technical background for
no it helps to have like a
base but like um not a lot
yeah like just it just enough so you can
have some conversation
but honestly sometimes it actually helps
to not have a lot because then
exactly the more you have the more that
you can get like mired and technical
conversations with
with developers and architects and
sometimes it helps just be able to say i
don't know how it works i don't care
just here's how it should look and act
and you don't really have to be
technical
to be able to say like i find that
confusing sometimes it helps to not be
technical for that part
it does help to be detail-oriented and
uh as opposed to a like a designer
would be more artistically oriented but
user experience
it can be like oh this button is is you
know
too far away from this other button so
it does actually get a bit fidgety
but like you know moving this button to
the other side of the screen would be
fewer movements for the person you know
most people right-handed but some people
are left-handed so you need to make it
switch over there so it's all about kind
of placement and colors and
using cognitive science on helping
people make
apps as useful as possible there's a lot
of studies on
contrast and distance um
and stuff like that so yeah there's also
a lot to be said for trying like
for trying to keep with standards across
other applications
because a lot people carry a lot of the
same sort of training and like how to
use software from app to app and if
you're trying to reinvent the wheel
that can be a real barrier to people
understanding what's going on
even though it might make sense
standalone you're like i think that this
is better
if it's in a huge contrast it ends up
really hampering adoption
yeah sometimes you'll want to break the
rules but like that hamburger menu
everyone complains about but
people are now trained for the last five
years
that's a menu button so we're kind of
stuck with it until
something else changes kind of like how
the the save button is still a floppy
disk even though those haven't existed
for
yeah i've been overall think of what to
do
and then i was having an issue because
you can like save to the cloud you can
save to your desktop you can save it
in your browser but if you go to another
browser it won't exist there
or if you lose all your cookies and
history if you erase your history
so giving them the concept and then
there's also like in memory saving like
did i did i actually make the change to
the data locally and then
where is it stored in all those three
places i'm like wow how do i explain
that
yeah it's tough the funny thing is that
even though people don't understand
the floppy disk they now associate that
with
we're saving and like there's you know
stories from parents who like they saw
a floppy disk and their kid is like oh
cool somebody 3d printed
the save icon like no that's actually
see if icon is based on but
i mean it's kind of like how the phone
icon is like the old you know
handset even though most kids have never
seen one of those
and it's still like they associate that
with the phone but the shape is
completely like why is that the shape
now whatever i just associate that with
the phone
that'd be funny if the button on a cell
phone was a picture of a cell phone
yes you're just like what it's just a
rectangle with icons
inside a rectangle with icons et cetera
right now the thing i'm using
so what's the button what's pressing the
button dude
it's actually really weird that an
entire generation doesn't know what all
these things are i mean i because i'm
deaf in one ear a lot of people get a
tattoo or something of the speaker with
a line through it right because that's
what mute is
oh that's cool and yet speakers also
aren't really something that you often
see like the
they're they're more because you do
still have external speakers when you
want
much better sound but not as much as you
know
it was basically given you it's also a
weird one because the speaker icon is a
part of the speaker that most people
don't see we're
sort of like the cone and the driver and
you're like why do we associate that
well they had to pick an icon and now
people know that as the sound even
though they don't know why
yeah there's always icons that we
associate with something that
most people now couldn't pinpoint why
yet they were only here for a very
small period of our history it's not
like we've had a phone
since you know the eighteen yeah we
haven't had a phone since
now i'm wondering when did the phone get
invented again maybe it was the late
1800s
but like not in the 1700s i will stand
by that there was not a phone
and the phone in the 1800s or what
whatever it was actually developed
didn't have that form factor it wasn't
that right it was like the separate
thing in the
yeah yeah the cone you held your ear
with the cable and the weird thing you
spoke into
i want to make that be the phone icon
there's a special psychological term for
this like reappropriation of uh
something
uh and turning into something new
uh leaving the old form uh i don't know
what the word is
i was trying to think of that i didn't
know there was a word
it's not anthropomorphic no it's
starting
who that they use the phone box and the
phone boxes
like it was even it was something so
innocuous that it could just be anywhere
when he would land anywhere in britain
but whatever he only went to britain
anyway
and then now it would stand out like a
sore thumb i think
a phone box where is superman supposed
to change
where are these things
i was at a police box which is like a
tardis on them
thursday with the because you have all
these pop-up shops outside these
tardis is being painted there light blue
instead of dark blue
these are the kind of things you don't
orchestrate right there was i don't
think anyone was sitting around being
like let's get rid of phone books
phone booths phone books yes can we
please get rid of those
there's still a few kicking around just
some people
the kids don't even wouldn't even get
the scene in superman
the movie when superman goes running
to try and find a place to change and he
looks over yeah and the phone booths
that just go from like the waist up to
just like that just a little half circle
thing
and he's like he has to go find
someplace else to
to change and now he just like runs real
fast and he just like
takes the clothes off in high speed like
he's the flash
that's part of like watching jetsons
which is horrible
jetsons and star trek both of which
were done in like the 60s 80s 90s and
their idea of the future when we've come
so far and yet not so far at the same
time and
the these are the kind what um
sharon said today in the game b space
something about i mean i read it today
actually i don't know if she said it
today
something about the or the difference
being complex and complicated
and how it's we're not
we can't orchestrate our way out of the
complicated right one person can't do it
it can't be really b
it has to be something complex and i
think there's there's something in that
like it's just the natural emergence of
continuing forward that makes these
things archaic not
sitting around deciding do we need
neither do we need an icon that's going
to last the test of time
because we would not have been able to
figure out what those would be or
are we going to let these things fall by
the wayside they just do
and they're obsolete
i mean the nice thing about using things
like the phone receiver and they say
you know the the floppy disk is that now
that they're ingrained
but they've gone away there kind of
won't be any competition for like things
that come back that might
confuse it people associate the phone
receiver with the phone
there's a good chance we're not going to
see something that's that kind of a form
factor
that's you know that wouldn't
immediately make sense for that so even
like you don't really have to know what
the phone is
or what the original thing was you just
see phone that's the icon
all right if i see that that icon from
now on i'll know that that's a phone
yeah so we might not need to it's just
weird to explain to people like no that
used to be a thing and now it only means
that concept even though you won't see
that physical thing anymore
it's like a tombstone of the phone wow
it's memorial to the phone everyone's
frozen but me
that's a problem technology
let's see 26 minutes in
do we want to just jump to any sort of
um together tech
or uh game b projects discussion
yeah we can one of the things we can
bring up which i was doing when i was
off camera
is uh one of the things adrian and i
talked about after the camera started
stopped rolling last time
was um if you have other electronic
devices
putting either the facebook or youtube
of us streaming
on that device so it looks like there's
more people watching so when the odd
person pops in
that's probably me watching another
device the odd person pops and they
don't feel like it's all on like the
spotlights on them like it sometimes can
feel
so there's two or three people here
people feel more likely to come in and
pop in a note and feel more
confident but that's not no one feels
the need
it's an invitation if you would like to
do that so we're gonna be ghosting then
yeah ghost watching exactly and it also
because if there's up to five either and
we could have multiple devices like
they're gonna be ten
of us on and it's just us watching so we
also won't know
if anyone's actually watching it works
both ways
we don't have to feel like someone's
watching
and when someone pops in they can
yes i imagine that would probably help
with the algorithm in all sorts of ways
but like afterwards being like oh
more people watch this live so more
likely to show it and it
might actually show up for more people
during the live
version of it like oh you know 10 or 15
people are watching this will
show it as opposed to if there's zero or
one i i don't think it really kicks in
to be like oh
not many people are interested in this
because not many people are interested
in this
yeah okay there was just one thing i
wanted to bring up in the calendar
so i know a few people have said they
could do 2 p.m
on a saturday alternative weeks
so are you wanting to change them and i
can put on the calendar or
badly is there any other stuff that i
need to put on the calendar before to do
the
project one which has all the people's
projects and
events and whatever in the group that
they're doing
uh i think it's good except um
you know the link i put on there is to
search for the tags
and if it's gonna be too challenging for
us i went ahead and tagged the one for
today and tomorrow
so they'll show up in that search so we
could either
create a new tag just for events and put
that on there and then we don't have to
worry about which one has tags and if
you go to that tag you'll
see the events you know that are going
on or the
light or the live stream or just
whatever we want to maybe a live stream
tag would be better
right so we could do that right so just
to do the tags for
the the board meetings and the idea
cafes
and the round tables yeah so if you do
those then people will find them but if
we forget to do that
um because it because it's automatically
posted when adriel and jubilee do it
they don't actually
do the post manually it's not tagged so
it won't show up in the list so the
instructions we gave them to find it
won't work
right okay so we need to either change
the instructions or change
or add that extra manual step
um so that's why
i wanted to get the main one done first
and then go on to the
the second one for the community events
like jubilee solution raisins and
whatever else that was happening now for
that one
rather than you having to maintain all
that and all the changes
um we can i mean maybe for jubilee or
for some people but
like if we want to have cesare put his
and um the stoa
put because they were posting one in our
group yeah
uh we can i generated a link
to where anyone who has that link
can put events on there all right it's
okay
no we don't if we sh we could share it
in the facebook group on a post but then
everyone on the internet can
see it it's not likely anyone is going
to see it
just the people in the group and then
anyone could post whatever they wanted
it just be a free-for-all
which is fine because that's why it's
not the main list
although i was thinking and i might be
going this too much is that
when you go to the main screen to look
at our things
it's not i mean there are two different
colors but
i'd almost like to have it have two
different
links um
because two completely separate
calendars rather than two calendars on
the same page
you know what i mean two counters on the
same partner that'd be my preference and
there might even be a way to create a
link to just view one
or the other i think there's a way just
because you can hide you can hide the
second one
you can hide yeah can you post a link
that auto hides it right because i'm not
talking about for me it's just
it'll be confusing to people people
won't be able to find our events if
there's all these other events going on
so it'd be nice if they have one link
for for the
official events and one link for the
project events
because i thought that was what was
happening anyway so when i go to the
link for the group they both show up at
the same time
and they're two different colors on the
left hand side
and then you can you have to um turn one
off to see the other
so it'd be nice if they if and i think
there is a way to make a link to where
you can only see one and length
yeah like keep them together adding
something to the url that indicates
which thing to enable or disable or
something like that
because i know you can create other
calendars but i don't know whether they
would show up on the same
the same link but i think you can
actually create
a different link or maybe if i set up
another group
but for that yeah so yeah give it a
separate
separate link yeah we may have to set up
a separate group in which case the link
i created
to let people create won't work because
they'll have to do
do a new one but but i think that's the
option and then we could just share it
through a private chat someone who's
posting a lot of things
just chatted to them say hey throw your
events on
right okay this calendar right it's okay
yeah i think that
oh also i don't know if we can within
the calendar because i know they're
they're color quoted for together tech
versus not
um but as a participant between which
ones
i am invited to be part of like what the
criteria is to watch it
criteria's probably not high to watch it
the criteria to participate
where i can watch it if i live and where
i can watch it if it's if i can watch it
after it's live
i don't think the calendar can
necessarily do all that you can do
in the descriptions
if you're putting the event up right you
can you could actually
create a page that would show it all up
in the description bit
yes i'm just wondering if like on the
calendar if i could see
like i don't know i know with the stoa
you have to be a member of them right so
that's part of the criteria i think to
be part of it but they might have the
odd event you don't need to be a cri
a member of to be able to see that so
i'm not going to click on all of the
stones to find the odd one
like to kind of say like maybe this is
only for ones that are open so people
come in and participate yeah
because i would think it would be better
on screen for people who are open
without them having to to join anything
that would be the criteria
of sort of like having it just for
people because like obviously you don't
want to be
putting stuff up there that people have
got to get through
all sorts of other stuff to get to
because then that's not really
kind of game b really is it because i
thought game b was about being open to
everybody
yeah no it's my game b it's not a slight
story
for the stole one you can register and
not be a member and go to those
but that's a fair point we we need to
tell anyone posting any things that
only post things that you might have to
register for but
um that you you can that anyone can
attend that there is a
barrier
so i guess i don't care if you want to
look to see if there's a way to separate
those two calendars
yeah we'll do i will have a look at that
until we got the first one sorted and
what what so are you happy with the
first one then
i think so and to yeah
yeah actually i don't know if that was
jubilee's point or i just misunderstood
her but
yeah on each one of those they can they
can go and see the playlists
that apply to them so they can always
catch up on the older ones
and then there's instructions on how to
get the stream yard link
so the strategy round table then when it
when are you wanting to start the 2pm
ones
or do you want to get a bit more
information first
i think we can try our first one a week
i was going to do tomorrow then i was
like it's probably a little too close we
haven't told people
that tomorrow will be 9 a.m and we'll
let people know
also that we'll hold the next week we'll
do 2pm because now that there's a
calendar
it's it was confusing to have fridays be
every other one is a board meeting and
an idea cafe
and on saturdays every other one is nine
and two without having a calendar to
show them which one's which
right which i don't know how it might be
easier to have it be the first second
the first third and fifth saturday are 9
a.m and the
the third well the other two
are the second and fourth
it's like the odds on nine a.m and there
you go the odds are on 9
i would want to a.m to make sure that
the repeating
function in the calendar app we use can
handle that easily so someone's not
having oh well i think so but you would
have to set up the
satisfaction you have to give him a
number right because i know we did it
for the
the board meetings and the idea cafe so
we had to set them up as separate
yeah from the same you know just we
carry it
one every two weeks you could do the
same with with the boards
meetings but i would need to number them
or
or some way of sort of like generating
different ones
for those two two weeks you know and
then it would fill them in
and you could i don't know it's probably
not appropriate to say morning and
evening but
because it's not morning in the evening
for some people
um maybe just call it a second
calibric road because it's it's because
of us
and australia and new zealand day so we
call it the yellow brick road
table homes like that
the kiwi uh kiwi week
okay anyone in that side of the
hemisphere is also welcome to start
creating things that are like more on
that side's
time zone it's just because it does feel
a little north american-centric to have
everything
during our day and it's like it has to
fit in
heaven forbid you have the australians
and then the europeans working together
we have to keep them separate well it
will be on our time
it'll be funny because they'll be from
the future
we'll be talking to them and they'll be
reporting back from the future
because
yeah and i was thinking it's probably
going to be confusing
uh so i guess everything's on
pacific time right now
but when the time zones change for the
people in the other
uk it's gonna switch for carry it's
gonna do october
every time this happens it's a disaster
between all the conversations we
schedule
it takes about four weeks to get
everything re-read
like they all change at different times
well what are they to put the
the current set of meetings to the end
of october
because that's when british summer time
changes
because i thought well if i go past
there then i've got the the
the changing and i thought nah so i just
did it to the end of october
till it changed and then then put
another set in because obviously people
have got
i don't know when daylight time starts
forever
the bd pdp st pdt
i don't know when pacific daylight time
starts
i would i still wouldn't separate them
to two different things we just got to
pick a time zone and
one option that i did for one of my
groups is i
picked utc but there are no time zones
and that just means universal time
coordinate a universal time
coordinated right they did it in french
so it's you know
it's not it's every universal
coordinated time is universal time
coordinated
so it's utc of course it's in it's you
have to say it with an accent
um
yeah let's just uh insult a large
country
that's why i was about to do it and then
i'm like oh my gosh that's not polite
anymore
previously known as gmt well no i mean
no
because gmt has uh has daylight savings
yeah yeah so utc does not have
daylight savings so that means
when in our summers if we have daylight
savings it would it would happen an hour
spring forward so what months does that
happen
earlier the the savings times what
what once does it happen for you because
it changes does it not happen
i literally that is not something i'm
going to put in my brain
it was the australian one is opposite to
us though so they we end up being two
hours different
for like a week or something no even
longer than that like
our make a conversation became slightly
like
oh sorry it's an hour to like once they
change we're an hour difference
it can be up to two hours different
during the whole
shit show for a few weeks and then it's
it's an hour difference
it doesn't go back to the same as it was
because they're going
yeah so they go forward and we go
backwards if everyone's okay with it i
would say put everything at utc
and then each individual has to they'll
see on their calendar they'll have to
know it's
it's nine o'clock during the winter and
ten o'clock during the summer okay
because you live in the country
pacific so that's but that's just a
suggestion let's see what everyone else
thinks
[Laughter]
okay just put a link in the private chat
i'm i'm wondering like if carrie
or matush used that link what time zone
is it showing you as
because i put one in earlier that
filters it down to just the calendar
but like it was a big long url that
contained my time zone
[Music]
the fact that we can put the time zone
means we might be even be able to put
like
here's the main calendar and then put
you know three or four links that would
translate it to that time zone so like
do one for pst one for utc one for
i don't know all you know one of the
australian times
so you said to you sent the one without
the time zone i mean i would rather have
it without the time so because it auto
detect
it it tries to auto detect the person's
time zone so
she said it wasn't your time zone nope
it wasn't how close was it
what was it it wasn't totally not close
enough
after 9 a.m
[Music]
part of it is also you have to click on
the side part where it says main
12 p.m main part you could be right on
the bottom right hand side too
there's a different link that actually
shows the main events one
uh so what we'll actually see it with
some content and so isn't this meeting
at
noon oh so you did figure out how to
create the links to hide the
other one yeah and then it sounds like
in those links as well we can also
include the time zones if we wanted to
so we could have like
here's a link for the main events in
vancouver time in australian time and
east time in utc
in the the different times but we we
need to figure out what the
sort of url parameter is because like in
the first
big gobbledygook thing i pasted in the
chat
it's got time zone equal america
vancouver
so we can probably find out what the
different codes are to put it in
i don't know i'll link it just give me
the the uk time
well really that's you know yeah it
wouldn't
it's supposed to be it's trying to auto
detect i would rather have it auto
detect until people look at the
right yeah if it's able to that's
i mean it didn't work for martush but um
what's it say in the bottom right hand
emails addresses and then i can add you
to it so you can add
stuff when you're ready
second
[Laughter]
yep you try this one
but when i changed the uh
link um so like
there's an example of that one for you
and then anybody that loads that
shit should see it in your time zone but
i think to bentley's point we only want
to use that
if it you know almost never does the
auto
detect if it's you know if it usually
does it i think he's right that we
should definitely err on the side of
you know here here's the link and then
you know if it doesn't auto detect maybe
we just have instructions on how to
change your own time zone
though uh the second time i entered this
uh very short link it actually auto
detected
i don't know what to do but i see you
also time so it's it's correct
at least though i don't know if it's if
it remember it from the previous uh
time i changed the time zone to see
all and then mine yeah oh this is
something
oh earlier we did not have the auto
detect on and then i found it and turned
it on so
i let's i'd try that until people
complain and just tell them to
be careful and check look in the right
hand bottom right hand um
and then carrie i don't know if you
noticed that adriel posted two links
one has the calendar highlighted and i
really like that because then you have
the option to see both calendars or just
one
and then in the introduction i would put
them as two separate calendars
for new people they see that and then
maybe post if you want to see them all
in one calendar
here's that link and i can probably edit
the
introduction although i want to make
sure that you feel comfortable editing
that information
well you know i'm quite happy with what
you do because you you have a tendency
to put things better
because me saying oh there you go
there's a link that's it
yeah no explanation there's a link you
have that
about it yourselves out
[Laughter]
although sometimes i get busy and well
if you get busy just just let me know
and i'll i'll go in there but the
technical stuff
i'm not too sure what to do with and as
i said i was just going to add it to
the page that you know the welcome
welcome page thing
that we've got in docs you know
oh that's what i was talking about i
think yeah because
you're better explaining things in the
business sense whereas i've got no
business sense at all
so look knock yourself out doesn't
wash quite well with uh people who are
businessly minded
yeah and just to uh to get those links
all
all you do is use the side panel on the
left like you can
add keywords you can select the calendar
and then when you want to do that just
hit share
and it opens up a new tab with all that
criteria in the url
and then you can do that
and then uh if you want to get fancy
after the the question mark like
the teamup.com id question mark
each of those things is a is a separate
thing separated by an ampersand
or by the end and then you can pick and
choose like i just sort of stripped out
all the stuff that wasn't
the calendar is equal and then that's
how we got to just calendars
i can't tell if they're using google
calendar as an actual base for the work
they did or if they just copied the heck
out of it
but either way it works unfortunately
their logo looks more like a calculator
than a calendar but
oh yeah i'm like calculator oh
no okay it's a calendar
yeah that's a lot like a calculator i
didn't even notice that but that's
they should have just left the top as
circles and it would have been more
well i think they're trying to be clever
and make a t out of the blue
yeah for team up so it's
yeah i guess maybe they could have just
not had to be a bar and had it be
bubbles as well
i i think that would be a little clearer
but for
seven days is still an odd number and
they could have had a t
with seven but that's a lot of dots for
a logo
but seven is a week and therefore a
calendar and three is very much a number
pad calculator
that's a good point the only thing is i
don't know if there's enough room on
because they also use it as an icon
for the browser tab yeah which then
you can make it smaller yeah because i
think you can
do the favicons i think you can you can
make them 32 by
32. and then yeah they would be smaller
dots but the question is when they are
we now solving team
calendars do look like calculators so
uh what they need to do is change the
icon to something like
um in the spirit of um old devices
uh giving uh shape to icons uh
of modern internet they should be using
something like a
paper scroll or something i don't know
what what people used
like long time ago for calendars
like books paper actually
a sundial yeah that's what i was trying
to think yes
there we go we'll use this seven
using icons for old things that people
don't know what they are anymore yeah
let's go all the way back to the sundial
maybe it is there any s
tools out there that are free forever
that you know of nothing's free
nothing's free no such thing as if you
either pay for it or you're the
or the goods being sold but no sorry
that's why eventually we're gonna have
to create one and if someone has to
create one that's free and readily
available and good
or we have to create it like because if
we have hundreds of people on something
paying
tens of thousands of dollars a month
doesn't make sense but recreating it for
absolutely does
okay it's just that ivana posted that
you know because obviously the chat
around the
creating a funding business or what have
you invested in that
um mentioned did was there such a thing
and i didn't think there was because i
know there's maybe a three
three so like sign up for 30 days
and then after that you get charged for
every member of the team
you know i mean when you don't even know
what the team's gonna be yet you know so
yeah i think it's very common of course
everyone has the same questions and the
same oh
social media let's create a social media
platform but it's
like right these are the same
conversations we've been having for six
months right is that now that being said
we've been looking for a calendar tool
for just that amount of time and we
somehow
like i don't think team up has only just
come into existence
in the last month
well that's the only one i found that
was really free
that you could actually you know
so maybe i guess what i'm saying kerry
if you found this one and you found open
collective maybe you're
the magic spider that gets something
right
i'll keep looking for stuff but as i
said a lot of the stuff that i've come
across
is either free for 30 days and then they
charge you a fee
and then they charge you for every
person that you have on the team
and then you can only and you have it so
you can you know
after 10 people you get charged more and
then you don't get off the things you
can you can't share with anybody so
you're basically just having to
keep it update yourself and share with
everybody and put you know what i mean
so
so yeah so i'll keep on looking for that
so copyright says 2014 so maybe they
have been around for a while i've been
looking for calendar apps
never ran across this i mean that's
funny this is why we need
to protect them because it is we like
how do these things exist when we're
looking for them trying to recreate them
and still
even when we're looking for them we
can't find them like
there needs to be one central place to
go and be like what are
the reasons is that those companies
offer free tools have to compete with
companies that
only offer paid tools and the companies
offer paid tools are going to be able to
you know pay for advertising and more
seo and of course that's why we
like not we is in the five of us but we
as in collective humanity need to solve
that problem to have one depository
repo repository to go to for
one reason i find them is actually when
i fall across
people doing projects and stuff and then
they go and have a nose and if they
maybe have a list i'm like oh
what does that do and so i have to go
digging through everybody's lists
like like a snoopy person that i am you
know i mean i'm just like oh look
so i don't know how would you create a
yelp then
what would you need to do for the for
the teammates team
uh game a not teammate get ready um
there is capterra.com which kind of does
that no it doesn't do
everything we said but it is kind of a
directory and so carry if you're looking
for other stuff i'd suggest
checking that out as part of your search
okay so and actually let's see if they
have team
oh yeah i think i looked at them and i
was going through the list and as i said
it was mostly free trials for
a period of time yeah
yeah yeah so and it's
yeah yeah so yeah i've been thinking
in um i'm also with the
open i'm working with open global mind
and
uh the the um
canonical debate lab group and they all
are trying to keep track of all these
people in the space that are doing
things like when kiala came out
and stuff we were like oh no um and open
global mind actually wants to use
a lot of these sense making apps and
stuff like that
and then i'm in i'm with this other
group called mighty minds and
we're going through methodologies on how
to work with groups and stuff like that
so i think this is really need for a
generic kind of app
to where you could have community a
community
driven um
directories searchable directories and
not just like random search but where
you can do rating and you can do
um categories like you you could say you
know it's good at this and
this is x you can you can just
fight then for that then say that again
it would just be a listing
listed what it would be it would be the
closest i would think would be
um and y'all i don't know if this is
just us based is a consumer reports
so you're going to buy a fridge and it
says okay so this one's
you can look at just the fidgets that
are 13.5 cubic feet
right cubic meters sorry for the rest of
the world
uh yeah and so you could narrow things
down by that and then also you could
rate it by like quality and easy to
repair and all this different stuff
um but but having that be community
driven
rather than you know paying researchers
to do it
right i think there's no system for that
in terms of community tools then you'd
have it like
free for the what's free for 30 days
it was free forever you'd have the free
trial and the free tiers and which
features cost what
yeah okay i think it would end up being
quite close to captera but without the
the game aids stand i think characters
started out being what we're talking
about
and then they found out oh we can
monetize this well i don't know if
they're
i mean they have reviews but it's not i
don't think it's
quite community driven true
yeah yeah but right yeah so like a
community-powered captain but like
with the idea of you can look for
certain sort of
for like the main features and one
product can have multiple features and
people can vote on it
and so i think it would be roughly the
same but with a
fair number of changes like it being
community driven and it being all about
just
is it good at serving the this purpose
not is this company paying us to say
they're good
yeah which is largely what kept here it
is now unfortunately
does that fit anything within your
system as far as the same thing because
you have organizations
you have companies are you going to want
to rate them on different metrics
at some point in the future so it's the
same tech
it's just companies rather than products
or um
totally yeah and long term i've got a
plan sort of under a different
umbrella but still sort of the same
database where you'd be able to look at
the products offered by a company um
more for physical products but it would
actually be easier to do it
for for digital ones so all right okay
right well i'll have a look at this as
well because i know i think i did look
at this because i was looking for the
crm software and i went through the list
and then i looked at the
the project management software and
there's all sorts of other stuff
that's out there yeah i don't know why
that why captera really
it just hurts my brain whenever i look
at it it's not that it's too complicated
it's something about their display or
something
to what open it no i
no i'm i don't have a bias against
corporate right now
i just like game b but i'm very
incorporated
no it's just i think they're filtering
and sorting and searching
just it's like almost detailed enough
but not quite and so it's this uncanny
valley it's like oh just give me a
search box or give me full control but
don't
um yeah so they have like free and free
trials monthly subscriptions
for those filter apps by that there
is and it says it's uh crowdsourced
there's
alternative2.net oh yeah okay let me
have a look at them
yeah always check that out too
i'm trying to see if they just have like
it's they tend to go more like i think
individual software like if you go to
alternative uh two dot net the home page
like if you scroll down they just got a
list of sort of the most common
applications so like
you can go look at alternatives to
photoshop and then it lists you know
sort of
image editors and okay you know you can
say
if they're free if they're paid okay
okay
what kind of license yeah alternative to
team
team up calendar they of course have
google calendar apple calendar
simple calendar mind time one calendar
web calendar digical
something called calendar what is it
about humans that
you know it's 2020 and we still for such
a basic functionality
uh we don't have it
and i think it goes to the same
thing that it took us so long to find
team up is that
everybody wants to sort of have their
say and have their version of it
and unfortunately with game a they end
up wanting to monetize it and then that
can kind of pollute the end purpose
and so you end up with you know a
million different alternatives
to these alternative seeking tools but
such a thing as calendar just
awesome yeah yeah
yeah oh so did we decide did we want to
just put everything on utc and not
change it
and everyone gets an hour off every
summer
or winter however you look at it summer
i guess because it's a shorter period
well as i said the current ones goes to
october so i don't know after october do
you want to change it then
just leave it as it is for now well it's
going to be confusing
oh cause i because i don't know doing it
at utc
i also think there's like a million
apocalypses that are going to happen
between now and october
so who knows what time changes will
happen between them
utc one there was two for usa in canada
and i just didn't know which one was
which
no there's a there's a utc utc it's
those are utc plus six and utc plus
something there's
just utc right that's the one without
time zones
so that's the one we'd want to switch it
to and then i would just have them go on
forever and hopefully remember to turn
it off if we ever stop doing a meeting
right okay where is the utc thing taking
like is that just the default you mean
or is that like
when we're listing the time in like the
text
or where is utc you have to also
anytime you put it in the text and we
have pdt or pst
we'd probably need to change that to the
utc time
and people are just going to have to
look it up like everyone who's not in
pdt pst right pacific time
i see so that's mostly when like either
a
the default of the calendar if it's not
if the auto sensing isn't working it
would default to utc
anytime that we're like typing out you
know
this meeting is at this time on this day
that would be
in in utc yeah
okay i think that that makes sense while
we're at it i suggest for the group we
go
to base six numbers instead of base 10
it's much more efficient you can because
you can divide it into thirds more
easily without having a rounding
decimal right we're good how about phase
12. i feel like it's
it's better so the guy the guy
there's a cool website that talks about
the comparison between base 12 and base
six
so whoa everything okay
everything messes up everything
literally and then we can just show the
raw binder now we fix
time zones the next need two more
numbers we can go to base 12.
yeah or we can get rid of four which
four are we getting rid of which four
digits are we
yeah you go from base ten seven eight
nine seven eight nine
that makes the most sense yeah
should we say goodbye to youtube
tomorrow at the usual 9 a.m i don't know
what that is in utc
but i will learn it well look at it i'll
look it up
i guess you see minus where you might
just yeah seven
ah i know um yeah which is rates
yeah going back to the basics to the
scenarios
so we're using hexadecimal then no it's
not like that's the smallest it's
exactly
60 60. all right okay
before we break more math youtube and
facebook bye